Husain Al-khulaif





Determined agile mindset with experience banking operations development, program management and strong business acumen represents a unique combination of disciplines with the drive and determination to consistently achieve success. I employ strategic thinking, business & technology innovation, thought leadership to cultivate a culture of change and reimagining the future to create and capture value to succeed in the customer-centric digital era.

#PMP & ACP & PSM Certified, MS. Computer Science, Banking Operations, Digitalization & Process Engineering and Robotic Automations, Data Analytics

EMPLOYMENT

11/2020-present Banque Saudi Fransi



Manager Center of Excellence, Central Operations Group

- * Leading the management of the bank central operations group projects delivery, service and operation development, budget control, process modeling and engineering, reporting and data analytics.
- * Central Operation wide projects portfolio management, include discovery and formation of initiatives, maintain project methodology, ensuring defined objectives and goals are met within time and budget constraint under various operational domains including Payments, Trade Finance, Treasury, Cards operations and Accounts services.
- * Providing impactful support to the end-to-end process design of operational processes that combine regulatory compliance and operational efficiency.
- * Support operation leadership on business cases development and studies, data analysis and discovery of potential areas of improvements, and plan and execute a course of actions to capture value of initiatives.
- * Conducting analysis and proposing solutions, understand business requirements and create functional specifications for different operational domains, keeping abreast of changing demands from multiple stakeholders and book of work initiatives.
- * Responsible for developing and delivering operational excellence strategy and support various business domains including managing internal change governance (as required), and process improvement solutions.
- * Supporting project management activities related to back-office operations in transformational initiatives including the Core Banking System (CBS) implementation and representing Central Operations Group in status and committee meetings.
- * Govern and manage Capital Expenditure (CAPEX), Operational Expenditure (OPEX) transversal cost lines, aliasing cost saving initiatives and financial & none-financial resources planning and performance.
- * Led the transformation of physical archives into digital for efficient document retrievals to fulfill SAMA and business lines periodic retrieval requests and safekeeping of bank documents.
- * Facilitated defining and execution of strategic initiatives for Central Operations Group to enhance the Internal Promoter Score (iNPS) enhancing and developing central operations services to optimize operational services to internal partners.
- * Perform data analytics, studies and reporting and presentation for management decision-making including reporting of performance and improvement in key operations services performance metrices.

O 6/2019–10/2020

Banque Saudi Fransi



Senior Business Analyst, Process Re-engineering Department, Demand Management Division

- * Performed business process analysis and modeling, and process re-engineering recommendations of cross-functional processes to reduce turn-around time and operational risk.
- * Managed the rollout of Robotics Process Automation (RPA) system and delivery of an automated bank processes to meet defined performance key strategic metrics using the RPA system (KPI: Turn-around Time, Human Resources and Operational Risk Reduction).
- * Actively conduct business analysis activities to discover gaps and opportunities, align with SME and obtain buy in of stakeholders for improvement opportunities and execute recommendations.
- * Coach a team of business analyst team to assess business needs and discover operational services enhancement opportunities.
- * Manage and control the execution of business analysis, projects management activities for both operation and cross business lines projects with securing alignment across all projects and stakeholders.
- * Provided leadership management with analytics and reports used for key decisions and steering committee meetings.
- * Maintain department dashboard for portfolio project progress, risks, scope and plan monitoring.
- Drive on priorities and work to ensure all stakeholders are aligned at each stage of the project lifecycle, ensure business, quality and functional goals are met with each project implementation.
- * Led fulfillment of SAMA no objection requirements for bank new initiatives including but not limited to the General Clearing Member (GCM).
- * Support project procurement efforts, vendor negotiation and service level agreement, and budget allocation and spending monitoring.

<u></u> 9/2017-5/2019

MEFIC Capital



Applications Assistant Manager, Information Technology Department

- Facilitated the development of IT strategy and execution of initiatives aligned with overall company vision with emphasis to digitalize onboarding and fund/investment subscription services and automate back-office operational processes to enhance customer experience.
- Managed the rollout, custom development and support of all company asset management and private equity business applications to manage products, back-office operations, and Saudi Stock Exchange online trading (TADAWUL) – Advent APX, Moxy and Tradex systems.
- Built the integration with third-party data acquisition including TADAWUL, Standard and Poor S&P, Bloomberg as well as back-office system integration to brokerage services provider for real-time and systematic stock trading and fund investment appraisal reporting.
- Business analysis of the capital market operations to identify fund management and operation demands, including Capital Market Authority (CMA) regulations and delivered cost-effective and optimal solutions.
- Undertaken a technical role in integration API development, batch automation, root-cause analysis and production issues resolution related to business applications, network and database engines.

04/2014-8/2017

Banque Saudi Fransi



Software Developer, System Integration Department, Information Technology Division

- Developed data acquisition processes and integration APIs (ETL- Extract, Transfer, Load) for bank channels, back-office applications and payment services.
- Developed automated financial reconciliations of various bank services and products accounts, nostro accounts along with automated workflow to rectify accounting discrepancies and resolution of customer complaints.
- Developed front and back-end software solutions and customization of existing systems in combination of architecture design, solution assessment and dependency analysis, development and integration testing, and system performance optimization.
- * Managed the execution of critical mission financial systems projects including a systematic upgrade, deployment of a new solution and data migrations.
- Responsible of overall technical support with a proven record of ability to diagnose issues in different IT functional domains (i.e., network, databases, back-end codes, security, architectural and integration related).
- Practical experience in general IT development utilizing technologies including but not limited to web development technologies, Java, C, C++, MS SQL, Oracle SQL (PL/SQL), SOAP API and Middle-ware technologies.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Executive Education

2021

2013 University of Colorado, USA \star Master Degree, Computer Science Completed and presented to graduate committee a thesis entitled: Public-Key Cryptography: Security-Based Analysis of the Underlying Intractable Problems. * \star Colorado State University, USA Bachelor Degree, Computer Science **Professional Certifications** \star 2018 Certified, Project Management Professional (PMP®), PMI * 2020 Certified, Professional Scrum Master (PSM I) 2021 Certified, Agile Certified Professional (ACP®), PMI **Training** Mindset Robotics Business Analyst, AutomationAnywhere Academy 2020 Robotics Program Management, AutomationAnywhere Academy 2021 Nano Degree, Business Analytics, Udemy

INSEAD, Digital Strategy in the Age of Digital Disruption

CORE COMPTENSIES

- Banking Operations & Systems
- Strategy and Digital Delivery
- Project Management, Agile, Scrum
- Business & Data Analysis
- Robotics Process Automation (RPA)
- Process Modeling and Engineering
- Gap Analysis, Opportunity Discovery
- Operation Model Design
- Budget Control (CAPEX/OPEX)
- Investment Banking
- Management Dashboards / Presentations
- Innovative and Entrepreneurial
- Business Relationship & Alignment
- IT Development & Support